Guide to the Cornell University maps, 1870-1995
Cornell University maps,
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Cornell University maps, 1870-1995
47/1/2788
Cornell University.
0.4 cubic feet, 2 mapcase folders
Printed Materials.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Printed maps showing the development of the campus. Includes map with information and statistics about the Cornell University Libraries.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Printed maps showing the development of the campus. Includes map with information and statistics about the Cornell University Libraries.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cornell University.; Cornell University -- Maps.; Cornell University
Form and Genre Terms:
Maps.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- A Map of Cornell University: The Cornell Grill, 1873-01-31 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  "Showing some of the buildings and roads and a good place to eat"; cartography by Larry Juna; handwritten annotation: "From: Mark Twain. DAVIE, FLORIDA"; hand-drawn map
- Cornell University Campus, 1896 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  With key
- Cornell Campus and Farms of the New York State College of Agriculture, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Cornell University Campus, 1900 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Campus map on front, map of relative position of university in Ithaca on back
- Cornell University Campus, 1900 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Cornell University Campus, 1900 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  With key; extra buildings printed
- Cyclorama of Cornell University, 1902 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Taken from McGraw Tower by S.L. Sheldon
- University Campus with New Athletic Field, 1903-07-15 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Cornell University Campus, 1905 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Cornell University Campus, 1906 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  With locations of fire alarm boxes, hoses, and hydrants in key
- Map of the Property of the Cornell University, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  By C.L. Crandall
- Cornell University Campus, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Hand-drawn; no key
- Cornell University and Vicinity, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  From surveys by College of Civil Engineering; by the Department of Military Science and Tactics
- Map of Campus and Dorms, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Initialed R.L.B. at the bottom
- Campus Map, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Campus Map with Key to University Buildings, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  With key; extra buildings printed; 2 copies
- Campus Map, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  With key; extra buildings printed; pencil markings
- Residential Section, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Shown together with map of city of Ithaca; 3 copies; prepared by STUDENT AGENCIES INC.
- Campus Map with Locations of Stay for Alumni, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  The back of map is titled Detailed Program of 1924 Reunion
- Campus Map, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Campus Map with Red Annotations, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Post-it on the back that reads: "1926 Internal Congress of Plants Scenics Map" but unclear handwriting
- Campus Map, Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  2 copies
- General Plan for Cornell University Plan Commission, 1925-11 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- General Plan for Cornell University Plan Commission, 1925-11-1926-04 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Residential Section and Campus, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Prepared by STUDENT AGENCIES INC.
- Residential Section and Campus, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Prepared by STUDENT AGENCIES INC.; this copy is presented by a different president and secretary-treasurer
- Residential Section and Campus, 1926 (Box 1)
- The Campus of Cornell University, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Campus Map and Traffic Regulation, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Unclear name on back of map: "Dr. Ken"; hand-drawn map
- Campus of Cornell University and Collegetown, 1934-09-24 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Advertisement for The Triangle Book Shop; hand-drawn map
- Campus Map, 1935-03 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Map of the Campus - Compliments of the Triangle Book Shop, 1939-09 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Campus Tour Map of the Willard Straight Hostess Committee, Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Guide map on the back; hand-drawn map
- Campus Map and a 30-minute Tour Route, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Suggested 30-minute tour indicated with red lines
- Campus Development Plan, 1942-01 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Prepared under direction of the Architectural Advisory Council
- Campus Map, 1945-06-01 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Map of Campus, Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Advertisement for The Triangle Book Shop
- Campus Map, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Campus Development Plan, 1946-05 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Campus Development Plan, 1948-05 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Campus Map, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Publicity for The Cornell Co-Op
- Campus of Cornell University, Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Campus of Cornell University, Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Advertisements on the back
- Campus of Cornell University and a 30-minute Tour Route, Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Suggested tour indicated with red lines
- Campus Map - Cornell Co-Op, Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Drawn by Dave Miller, photo science lab
- Campus of Cornell University, Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Compliments from the Co-Op (students' store); advertisement on the back
- Campus of Cornell University - "A Map to Help You Find Your Way to The Cornell Co-Op", Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Similar map as the other campus maps but with a different advertisement for the Co-Op on the back
- Campus of Cornell University, Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Annotation of Balch Hall
- Map of Campus and Collegetown - Compliments of The Triangle Book Shop, Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Hand-drawn map
- Map of Campus and Collegetown - Compliments of The Triangle Book Shop, Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Added details and some changes to roads on map; hand-drawn map
- Campus Map, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Campus Development Plan, 1951-06 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Campus Map, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Campus Development Plan, 1954-01 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Campus Development Plan, 1954-01 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Red marks on buildings
- Plan for the Improvement of the Cornell University Campus, Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  By landscape architect Charles Lowrie
- Copy of Campus Map from The Cornell Desk Book, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Map of Campus Parking, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Map of Campus Parking, 1977-08 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Map of Campus Parking, 1978-08 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Map of Campus Parking, 1979-08 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Map of Bus Services and Routes, 1980-06 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Includes information about parking permits
- Transportation Services Map, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Includes information about parking permits and bus services
- Campus Bus Routes and Visitor Parking, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Cornell University Libraries, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Overview of university libraries on the back
- Campus Map - Visitor Parking and Walking Tours, Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Campus Map - Visitor Parking and Walking Tours, Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Few added details compared to first Campus Map - Visitor Parking and Walking Tours
- Campus and Area Maps, Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Map of Central Campus, University Campus, and campus in relation to Ithaca
- Interests Abroad - Cornell University Around the Globe, 2002-04 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Cartography and Layout by Scott Hayward; shows locations of Shoals Marine Laboratory, Arecibo Observatory Puerto Rico, and Weill Cornell Medical College in Qatar
- Campus of Cornell University and Vicinity, 1928 (Mapcase-folder 1)
  Designed by Ellen Edmonson; ornate drawn design; quotes along border